SpaceX的载人龙飞船是首个由商业航天公司发射的载人飞船
The SpaceX Crew Dragon is the first spacecraft
from a private company to take humans into space.
本期视频我们将看看它的内部 对其有个大致了解
In this video, we're gonna take a look inside and see how it works.
并看看它如何从发射架直冲云霄
Then we'll see the launch pad, the journey into space,
最终如何与国际空间站回合的
and how it docks to the International Space Station.
SpaceX的载人龙 你已获准发射!
Dragon, SpaceX, you are go for launch!
工商时间 跳转01:20
我们即将了解到一个克服了重重挑战的工程
We're about to learn about an incredible piece of engineering that has overcome significant challenges.
为了克服这些挑战 工程师需要大量时间学习解决问题的技能
To solve these challenges, engineers need problem solving skills that take time to develop.
因此 非常感谢Brilliant对本期视频的赞助
This is why I'm glad to have this video sponsored by brilliant.org
在Brilliant 你能通过互动的方式学到数学与科学
With Brilliant, you can learn math and science interactively.
你可以积极尝试 了解事物的运作方式
You can actively try things out and understand why things work the way that they do.
你可以是一个想提高技能水平的专业人士
Maybe you're a professional and wanna level up your skills
也可以是想更好理解数学的小学生
or maybe you're still in grade school and want a better way to understand math.
Brilliant有成千上万不同的领域课程可供选择
Brilliant has thousands of lessons to choose from in a variety of different areas
你可以随时随地学习
and you can learn anytime, anywhere.
我真的很喜欢一些数学课
I've really enjoyed some of the math lessons
因为你能以一种课本教不了的方式来看待事物
because you get to see things in a way that just won't happen with a textbook.
你可以前往下方网址免费试用30天
You can try everything Brilliant has to offer for free for 30 days by going to brilliant.org/JaredOwen
前200人将获得Brilliant年度高级会员的20%折扣
the first 200 people will get 20% off Brilliant's Annual Premium membership.
载人龙飞船是一款载人飞船
The Crew Dragon is a human rated spacecraft.
它可以将人类送入太空
This means it's capable of carrying humans into space.
它由一家名为SpaceX的美国私人公司制造
It was created by United States private company called SpaceX.
公司的总部在加利福尼亚州霍索恩
The company has its headquarters in Hawthorne, California.
到目前 太空探索一直由拥有数十亿美元经费的政府主导的
Up until now, space exploration has been done by government agencies who have billions of dollars to spend.
SpaceX是第一家打破这一惯例的私人公司
SpaceX is really the first private company to break through this barrier.
他们独立研发了火箭与载人飞船
They develop both rockets and spacecraft on their own,
但当然 NASA现在是SpaceX的最大客户
but of course NASA is now under the largest customers of SpaceX.
先为大家介绍一些背景内容 视频中所示为国际空间站 (ISS)
All right for some background, this is the International Space Station or ISS for short.
它从2000年左右开始运营
It's been in use since the early 2000s
需要不停送宇航员往返于次 保持有人常驻状态
and it must be continuously staffed by astronauts going to and from the station.
想要前往国际空间站
To get a ride to the ISS,
宇航员可以乘坐美国的航天飞机或俄罗斯的联盟号飞船
astronauts could launch on either the United States Space Shuttle or the Russian Soyuz Spacecraft.
航天飞机已于2011年退役 不再运营
The space shuttle is no longer in operation, it was retired in 2011.
此后 联盟号成为往返国际空间站的唯一途径
After that, the Soyuz was the only way to travel to the ISS.
前往国际空间站再无其他选择
There was no other spacecraft available to take humans into space.
2020年 这一情况有所改变
The year 2020 changed all of this.
载人龙飞船 让宇航员再次从美国本土飞向太空
The Crew Dragon flew astronauts once again from American soil.
龙飞船有几种不同版本
The Dragon Spacecraft has a few different versions.
首先是"龙一"
First came Dragon One.
这是一款货运飞船 可以为ISS输送补给
This was a cargo spacecraft that brought supplies to and from the ISS.
它已经为国际空间站送了超过20次货物
It had more than 20 flights bringing cargo to the station.
该版本的飞船无法载人 只能送货
This version of the spacecraft could not carry humans, only cargo.
之后是"龙二"
Then came the Dragon 2.
分为两个版本 货运龙和载人龙
This has two versions, the Cargo Dragon and the Crew Dragon.
载人龙可以送宇航员和货物进入太空
The Crew Dragon can carry people and cargo into space.
货运龙外观上很相似 但只能运送货物
Cargo Dragon looks very similar, but it can only hold cargo.
因此无需维生设备 逃逸发动机 舱内也没有控制
So it doesn't need life support, aboart engines, or controls inside the vehicle.
本期视频我们将重点介绍载人龙飞船
For this video, we'll be focusing on the Crew Dragon.
最令人兴奋的一款——将人类送入太空
That's the part that's most exciting to me, bringing humans into space.
载人龙飞船分为两个部分
The Crew Dragon is split up into two parts.
"trunk" 有树干 行李箱的意思
上面是舱段 下面是柱段
This is the capsule and this is the trunk.
舱段也是加压区
The capsule is also known as the pressurized section.
内部有可供宇航员呼吸的空气与舒适的温度
Inside, there's air to breathe and they keep the temperature nice and comfortable for the crew.
顶部是鼻锥
This is the nose cone.
发射时关闭
It's closed for the launch
入轨后会很快打开
but they will immediately open it up once they are in space.
从而暴露出内部的传感器 推进器
This exposes some sensors, thrusters
和用于与国际空间站对接的对接机构
and the docking mechanism that will be used to attach to the ISS.
龙飞船有16台天龙座推进器
The Dragon capsule has 16 Draco thrusters.
12台在四周 4台在顶部
12 of them on the side and then 4 more up towards the top.
天龙座推进器可以调整飞船的姿态
Draco thrusters are used to change the orientation of the spacecraft.
还可以用来给飞船变轨
They're also used to change the spacecraft's orbit
让飞船在任务初期能够与国际空间站交会
so they can reach the ISS at the beginning of a mission,
并在任务后期进行离轨点火 返回地球
and then de-orbit at the end of a mission and come back to Earth.
另外 龙飞船还有八台超级天龙座发动机
Additionally, there are eight super Draco engines
它们的推力大得多
and these are significantly more powerful.
从发射台到入轨期间如果发生任何意外
If there is an emergency on the launchpad all the way up until they are in orbit,
超级天龙座可以快速将宇航员带到安全区域
the super Draco engines can quickly get the crew to safety.
龙飞船舱段底部是防热大底
On the bottom is the heat shield.
它能在任务结束返回地球时保护宇航员
This will protect the crew as they enter the Earth's atmosphere at the end of the mission.
最初 SpaceX的设计是从防热大底伸出着陆腿
At one point, SpaceX had plans to have landing legs
and extend them through the heat shield.
这样飞船可以在陆上着陆
This is so that the capsule could touch down on land.
效果估计会很酷炫
This would've been really neat to see.
但因为复杂度与时间关系
However, due to cost complexity and time schedule,
SpaceX放弃了这个设计 决定让飞船溅落海中
SpaceX turned away from this idea and decided to do a splashdown in the water
类似NASA过去其它飞船那样
like other NASA spacecraft have done in the past.
龙飞船的下半部分是柱段
The bottom half of the spacecraft is called the trunk.
里面可以放置货物
There's room for cargo in here
还能在发射时支撑上部的舱段
and it helps support the spacecraft during the launch.
柱段白色那一半有散热面板
The white half of the trunk has the radiator panels
可以辅助飞船散热
which help remove heat from the spacecraft.
另一半蓝色的部分是太阳能电池板
The other side covered in blue is the solar panels.
可以为龙飞船提供电能
This generates power for the Dragon capsule.
前一版本的龙飞船使用太阳帆板 在入轨时展开
The previous version of Dragon had solar panels that would unfold once in space.
但如果展开失败 就会很麻烦
This can be problematic if the panels ever fail to unfold.
因此这种贴片的太阳能电池板就很方便
So what's kind of nice to have the solar panels directly on the side,
让它对着太阳就有电了
just point it towards the sun and you've got power.
柱段会在整个任务中一直跟随舱段
The trunk stays attached for the entire mission.
直到任务末期 在溅落前一小时左右分离
It's only detached at the very end, about an hour before splash down.
柱段没有防热大底
The trunk does not have a heat shield.
它落回地球时会在大气层中烧毁
It will fall back to the Earth and burn up as it enters the Earth's atmosphere.
宇航员使用侧面的舱门进入舱段
To enter the capsule, astronauts use the side hatch.
载人龙飞船设计最多可以载7人
The Dragon capsule was designed to fit up to seven people inside.
而NASA只使用其中四个座位
However, NASA has chosen to use only four of the seats.
座位下面的空间可以放货物
This leaves more room to carry cargo underneath the seats.
龙飞船是一款现代飞船
The Crew Dragon has been described as a modern spacecraft.
座位是根据每位宇航员定制的 内部空间很大
The seats are customized to the body of each astronaut and there's a lot of room.
拿它和联盟号飞船相比的话……
Compare this to the Soyuz spacecraft which …
联盟号空间是真的挤
Well, see for yourself, there's not a lot of room in there.
让我选 我肯定坐载人龙飞船
If I had the choice, I would choose the Crew Dragon.
宇航员坐好后 他们的座位会旋转
Once the astronauts are fully strapped in these seats will be rotated.
龙飞船可以由三块触摸屏显示器控制
The Crew Dragon can be controlled by the three touchscreen displays.
直到现在 多数飞船还都使用大量的物理按键 旋钮 开关 仪表盘
Up until this point, most spacecraft have had tons of physical buttons, lots of knobs, switches, and dials.
SpaceX决定使用这种充满未来感的面板
SpaceX has decided to go with the sleek futuristic panels.
下方有一些物理按钮 防止上方面板故障
There are a few physical controls just in case the panels fail.
绝大多数的飞行都是全自动的
Most of the flying is done autonomously
都是由飞船上的计算机自主完成的
which means most of it is done by the computers on board.
正常情况下宇航员并不需要做太多事情
All goes well, the astronauts won't need to do much.
飞船内有几个窗户可以看到外面
Inside the cabin are several windows to look outside.
想方便的话 可以使用天花板这里的厕所
And if you need to use the bathroom in space you can use the toilet up towards the ceiling.
我们对这部分细节知之甚少 但我感觉隐私不是很好
We don't know too many details here but let's just say privacy as somewhat limited.
中间是对接舱门
Right in the center is the docking hatch.
宇航员通过这里进入国际空间站
This is where the astronauts will go through to get on board the ISS.
我们将在稍后介绍这部分
We'll talk more about this later in the video.
飞船舱段的底部称为服务段
The bottom part of the capsule is referred to as the service section.
里面有飞船的电子设备与燃料罐
This has more electronics and fuel tanks for the spacecraft.
SpaceX将他们的飞船设计为可重复使用的
SpaceX designs their spacecraft to be reusable.
太空环境很恶劣
Space is hard.
从太空那样的环境走一遭后返回地球
The harshness of space and getting back down to earth.
很多航天器只能使用一次
This usually means that a spacecraft can only be used once,
至少之前都是这样做的
or at least that's how it's usually been done.
每次发射都要造全新的飞船
You have to build a new one each time
花费大量的钱
and this costs a lot of money.
而载人龙飞船设计就是可复用的
With the Crew Dragon Capsule, it's designed to be reused.
至今生产的载人龙飞船一只手都数得过来
There are handful of vehicles that have been built so far,
每个都有序列号和代号
and they each have a serial number and they have a name as well.
截至2023年2月 其中几艘已经飞行超过一次
As of February, 2023, some of these have been flown more than once.
2020.05.30 Demo-2任务
2021.04.23 Crew-2任务
2022.04.08 Axiom-1任务
即将执行Crew-6任务
其中奋进号已执行过三次飞行任务
And Endeavour has been flown three times.
2020年5月 载人龙飞船首次载人飞行任务
The first time a Crew Dragon has been flown with a crew on board is May of 2020.
两位NASA宇航员成功与国际空间站对接
There were two NASA astronauts on board that successfully docked to the International Space Station.
此后 载人龙飞船还执行了多次任务 其中不只有NASA
Since then, the Crew Dragon has flown more flights not just from NASA,
甚至还有一次搭载四名平民的飞行任务 "Inspiration 4"
but there was a flight of four civilians called Inspiration 4,
还有一家名为"公理航天"的私人航天公司的飞行任务
and also a flight from a private space company called Axiom Space.
本期视频发布时 还有很多计划中的任务
At the time of of this video, there are more missions planned as well.
这些都实实在在改变了航天工业的游戏规则
Things are definitely changing in the space industry.
载人龙飞船由猎鹰九号火箭发射 火箭也由SpaceX研制
The Crew Dragon is launched on top of a Falcon 9 rocket which is also made by SpaceX.
Falcon: 猎鹰 隼
火箭的名字来自星球大战里的"千年隼"
This rocket gets its name because of the Millennium Falcon from Star Wars.
跑题了但挺酷的
That's pretty cool if you ask me.
火箭从佛罗里达州肯尼迪航天中心发射
The launch takes place at Kennedy Space Center in Florida.
这里是发射复合体39A (LC-39A)
This is launch Complex 39A.
这里曾进行过很多历史性的发射
It's where some of the most historic launches have taken place.
现在它归SpaceX所用 变得也有一点点不一样
But now SpaceX gets to use this launchpad and it looks just a little bit different now.
NASA之前一直是让火箭垂直运输到发射台的
NASA has always transported rockets vertically to the launchpad.
称为垂直转运
This is called the rollout.
SpaceX则有一点点不一样
SpaceX has decided to do things just a little bit differently.
发射架旁边就是火箭的水平总装车间
Right next to the launchpad is the horizontal integration facility.
猎鹰九号火箭和载人龙飞船会水平姿态进行总装
The Falcon 9 Rocket and Crew Dragon are assembled in the horizontal position.
之后它们会在运输起竖装置上缓慢运输到发射架
Then they are slowly moved on top of the transporter erector.
然后缓慢竖起到垂直位置
Then it's slowly lifted up to the vertical position.
通常要花几小时
This usually takes several hours.
俄罗斯的联盟号火箭也是水平转运的
The Russian Soyuz rocket is transported horizontally.
他们从六十年代就这样操作了
They've been doing it this way since the 1960s.
所以不算新鲜
So this is nothing new.
只是在美国 水平转运和NASA以往的做法不太一样
It's just a bit different from the way that NASA normally does things here in the US.
发射当天 宇航员会穿上SpaceX的宇航服
On the day of the launch the astronauts get into their SpaceX spacesuits.
然后乘坐特斯拉Model X电车前往发射台
And then drive to the launch pad in a Tesla Model X.
伊龙·马斯克是SpaceX和特斯拉的创始人
Elon Musk founded SpaceX and Tesla.
所以让宇航员坐特斯拉前往猎鹰九号发射台再合适不过了
So it's only fitting that astronauts ride in a Tesla on their way to the SpaceX launch.
火箭旁边的黑色建筑是发射塔(直译:固定服务设施)
This is the fixed service structure.
宇航员乘坐电梯到达顶部
The astronauts ride up an elevator to get to the top,
之后通过登船臂
then walk across the Crew Access Arm.
white room "白色房间"
NASA从水星计划 阿波罗 航天飞机 再到现在
宇航员登船前进行最后准备的房间
登船臂的尽头是"白色房间"
At the end is the white room.
会有几名工程师帮助宇航员进入飞船
Several technicians will be there to help the astronauts get into the capsule.
称为宇航员进舱
This is called crew ingress.
即宇航员进入龙飞船舱段
It's the word they use to describe the crew getting into the Dragon capsule.
一共四个座位
There are four seats.
中间两位是指令长和驾驶员 两侧是任务专家
We have the commander, pilot, and then two mission specialists on the very ends.
所有人坐好后 座位向后旋转来到准备发射的姿态
Once they are all strapped in, the seats recline their laid back position ready for the launch.
并且指令长与驾驶员也能更方便触及到三块触摸屏
The commander and pilot are now in a good position to use the three touchscreens.
他们会在发射前两小时左右落座
They're in their seats about two hours before the launch.
发射前45分钟 登船臂收回
45 minutes before the launch, the crew access arm is retracted.
发射前35分钟 猎鹰九号推进剂开始加注
35 minutes before the launch, the propellant begins loading into the Falcon 9 Rocket.
猎鹰九号是两级火箭
Falcon 9 is a two-stage rocket.
一级由9台梅林1D发动机提供动力
The first stage is powered by 9 Merlin 1D engines.
也因此这款火箭名为猎鹰九号 因为一级有九台发动机
That's also why they call it the Falcon 9 because there are 9 of these engines.
二级由单台梅林真空发动机提供动力
The second stage is powered by a single Merlin vacuum engine.
这款火箭属于"部分可复用"火箭
They call this a partially reusable rocket.
他们的目标是完全可复用 但目前还做不到
The goal is to be fully reusable, but we're not there yet.
火箭的二级无法复用 每次发射都会消耗掉
The second stage is not reusable or in other words, it's expendable.
目前没有更好的办法能让它平安回到地面
We don't have an easy way to get it back down to the ground.
而猎鹰九号的一级却能在几分钟后回收 我们稍后会展示
The first stage, however, is reusable and in just a minute, I'll show you how this works.
所以画面中的整枚火箭里
So our full rocket stack here,
只有上面的飞船舱段和下面的一级是可回收的
the only pieces that are reusable are the capsule and the first stage.
大家有时可能看出一级是不是用过的
You can sometimes tell if the first stage is being re reused
因为复用火箭看上去不那么新
because it won't look quite as new.
发射最激动人心的时刻就是起飞阶段了
The most exciting part of every launch is the liftoff.
直播中最常听到的话就是"正常"两个字了
Something you'll hear the controllers say is the word nominal.
我们会听到"发射正常"或者"分离正常"
They'll say, we have a nominal launch or a nominal separation.
这是火箭发射中最美的语言了
This is a very good word to hear.
这意味着一切都按计划进行
It means that everything is going as planned.
一级火箭会在2分40秒关机
The first stage shuts off at 2 minutes and 40 seconds.
称为主发动机关机 MECO
This is called MECO or main engine cutoff.
之后一二级分离
Then the first stage separates.
紧接着二级点火
Then the second stage fires up.
它会把我们送入近地轨道
This is what gets us into orbit around the earth.
当二级火箭工作的时候
While this second stage is firing
一级火箭自己会自行返回地球
the first stage makes its way back to the ground.
一级火箭使用冷气推进器调整姿态
The first stage uses cold gas thrusters to reorient itself.
这一步称为"翻转机动"
This is called the flip maneuver.
它还会展开格栅舵来辅助稳定
Grid fins also come out to help stabilize it.
一级火箭会降落在海上
The first stage will come down over the ocean
因此到时会有一艘无人拖船在着陆点等待
so they will have a drone ship waiting at just the right spot.
再入点火可以让火箭进入浓密大气前减速
The entry burn helps to slow it down through the atmosphere.
此过程使用三台梅林发动机
This only uses three of the Merlin engines.
着陆点或可能是一台或三台发动机点火
依剩余燃料而定
在着陆之前
And just moments before touchdown,
会有一台发动机点火
one more engine lights up for the landing burn,
接着四条着陆腿展开 准备最终接地
and then the landing legs are deployed for the final touchdown.
无人拖船之后会回到佛罗里达州
The drone ship can make its way back to Florida,
让一级火箭重新用于未来任务中
so this first stage can be reused on a future mission.
二级火箭会继续将载人龙飞船进入近地轨道
The second stage is going to get the Dragon spacecraft into orbit around the earth.
这一过程称为"轨道插入"
This is called orbit insertion.
二级火箭会在大约8分50秒时关机
Second stage cuts off at 8 minutes and 50 seconds.
称为二级发动机关机 SECO
This is called SECO or second engine cutoff.
随即船箭分离
Shortly after the second stage separates.
之前提到过 二级火箭无法复用
As we talked about earlier, the second stage is not reused.
它会自己回到地球 在大气中烧毁
It makes its way back down to the earth and burns up in the atmosphere.
另外 上述的这些事件其实是同时发生的
Now keep in mind, that a lot of these events are happening simultaneously.
这样 龙飞船就自由啦
The Dragon spacecraft, it's on its own now.
鼻锥打开 暴露出对接口附近的传感器与推进器
The nose cone opens up to expose the docking hatch sensors and thrusters.
航天员也会首次感受到失重
The crew will also be weightless for the first time.
入轨后 就该去追国际空间站了
Once in orbit, it's time to catch up to the ISS.
多数任务中 该操作需要24小时
Most missions take around 24 hours for this to happen.
天龙座推进器会工作几次来提高轨道
The Draco thrusters are used several times to raise the orbit,
慢慢缩小与空间站的距离
and close the distance to the station.
航天器与国际空间站对接通常有两种方式
To attach a spacecraft to the station, they do it in one of two ways.
非合作目标交会对接 与 空间交会对接
One is called berthing and the other is called docking.
首先是非合作目标交会对接
First let's talk about birthing.
初代龙飞船 龙一 就是这种模式
This is what the original Dragon spacecraft or Dragon 1 would do.
它会飞到国际空间站旁边
They would fly right up next to it
国际空间站的机械臂会伸出
and the station's robotic arm would reach out
抓住航天器 将它与自身对接
and grab onto the spacecraft and help bring it in.
这就是非合作目标交会对接
This is called berthing.
稍微帮它一下才能与我们对接
We just need a little help to join to the station.
普通的空间交会对接也类似
Docking is similar
但这时航天器可以不靠机械臂的帮助 自行完成对接
but this time the spacecraft can do it all on its own without the help of a robotic arm.
载人龙飞船就是这样的 称为空间交会对接
This is what the Crew Dragon does. It's called docking.
国际空间站建造过程 av41754103
我们再观察一下国际空间站
Let's take a minute to look at the ISS again.
载人龙飞船会从前向与国际空间站对接
The Dragon spacecraft will dock towards the front of the station.
此处称为"节点舱2" 或"协和号节点舱"
This is called node two or the harmony module.
它上面黑色的是加压对接适配舱 PMA
Attached to it is the Pressurized Mating Adapter or PMA for short.
国际空间站上一共有三个PMA
There are three of them.
PMA-1在空间站中部
PMA-1 is in the middle of the station,
前部是PMA-2和PMA-3
and then at the front is PMA-2 and PMA-3.
最后一次在PMA-2上对接的正是航天飞机
The space shuttle actually was last docked here to PMA-2.
那都是2011年的事情了
This was back in 2011.
IDA一共有两个 都安装在协和号节点舱上的两个PMA上
之后 他们在上面加装了一个国际对接适配器 IDA
Since then, they've added the international docking adapter or IDA for short.
它用来与龙飞船使用的新款对接机构对接
This uses the newer docking mechanism that Crew Dragon is also using.
因此 龙飞船在国际空间站上有两个可用的对接口
So Crew Dragon is able to dock at two different locations.
多数任务都会使用空间站的前向对接口
Most of the missions so far have docked to the very front of the station.
为了准备对接 龙飞船会伸出它的软捕获环
In preparation for docking, Crew Dragon will extend the soft capture ring.
载人龙飞船会一次到达几个保持点
Crew Dragon Spacecraft will go through a series of waypoints,
保持点是空间站附近供航天器暂时停留进行全面检查的位置
and these are points in space where they will stop and complete checks
保证航天器状态良好 可以进行后续对接任务
to ensure that the spacecraft is in good condition to proceed with docking.
首先是保持点0
First we have Waypoint 0.
它在国际空间站正下方400米处
This is 400 meters directly below the ISS.
接下来是保持点1
Next is Waypoint 1.
它在空间站前向220米处
This is 220 meters directly in front of the station.
龙飞船会在此时让自己的对接口与国际空间站的目标对齐
They will line up along the docking access always pointing the capsule towards the docking port.
接下来龙飞船会缓慢靠近保持点2
Then they will slowly proceed to Waypoint 2.
它在对接口前方20米处
This is 20 meters in front of the docking port.
随着飞船继续靠近
As it slowly moves in
大家可以看到天龙座发动机不断点火工作保持与空间站对齐
you can see the Draco thrusters firing to keep it in line with the station.
一切确认完毕 航天器会继续执行对接
Once confirmed, then the spacecraft proceeds to dock,
但此时速度只有每秒几厘米
but moving only at a few centimeters per second.
当距离对接口只剩5米时
Once within 5 meters of the docking port
飞船会到达宇航员脱手点 CHOP
they have what's called CHOP or crew hands off point.
此刻以后 任何终止对接的决策都要由飞船计算机完成
If any aborts are needed at this point, it will be done completely by the onboard computers.
然后 软捕获环与空间站对接
Next, the soft capture ring on the Crew Dragon makes contact with the station.
称为"软捕获"
This is called soft capture.
我们已与空间站相连 但还差一点
We've connected with the station, but it's not complete yet.
捕获环会慢慢收回 将飞船拉近
The ring slowly retracts to pull the spacecraft in.
这样 "硬捕获"就完成了
This part is called hard capture.
12个锁止机构锁定 让飞船与空间站牢牢固定
The 12 hooks will latch to firmly connect it to the station.
大约需要两个小时才能完成对接
It will take about two hours before docking is complete.
我们先在过渡段内充入空气
First, we fill the vestibule with air.
这里是飞船与空间站之间的空间
That's the area between the spacecraft and the station
国际对接适配器之内
right inside the international docking adapter.
当其中温度与气压都正常后
Once the temperature and pressure have normalized,
异体同构周边式对接机构(APAS)内的舱门打开
then the APAS hatch can be opened,
最后是载人龙飞船的舱门
and then finally the Dragon hatch.
是时候与国际空间站内的宇航员们打招呼啦
Now it's time to say hello to the astronauts that are already on board this station.
我是Jared 我喜欢制作3D动画解释各种东西的原理
My name's Jared, I create 3D animations to show and explain how things work.
欢迎去看我的其他视频 欢迎关注
Click the cards to watch another video or click here to subscribe.
感谢观看 我们下期视频见
Thanks for watching, and I'll see you next time.